# John Brodeur

EMAIL: jbrodeur001@gmail.com

PHONE: (401) 450-9012

LOCATION: Columbia, CT 06237

LINKEDIN: /jpdbrodeur | GITHUB: /JPDBrodeur | PORTFOLIO: jpdbrodeur.github.io/portfolio

\_\_\_

# Full-Stack Web Developer with a background in teaching, IT, graphic design and digital communications. Trained at the

university of Connecticut's coding boot camp and certified in full-stack web development. Innovative problem-solver focused on mobile-first UX and strategically improving web applications. Wielding a refined set of soft skills from years of team collaboration, mentoring and management experience.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages	Frameworks & Libraries		Tools		Methods
HTML5	Bootstrap	Mongoose	Photoshop	MongoDB	AJAX
CSS	Express.js	Node.js	InDesign	MySQL	APIs
JavaScript ES6+	Handlebars	ReactJS	Git	Sequelize	JSON
SQL	jQuery	Tailwind	GraphQL	Webpack	Mobile First

### **PROJECTS**

## Fomo Mock Exchange | Models, Routing & Styling

Deployed: fomo-exchange.herokuapp.com | GitHub: github.com/RynMrphy18/fomo-mock-exchange

- A stock trading site for people who want to become familiar with the stock market without risking their personal earnings in the process! Research, buy and sell with a \$500 initial budget.
- Configured transaction model, data rendering, page routing, responsive layout & styling
- Tools / Languages: JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, Yahoo Finance API, Bootstrap, Handlebars, Bcrypt

**Vaccidate** | Models, Mutations, CRUD Operations, Profile Form, Framework Configuration Deployed: powerful-basin-63649.herokuapp.com | GitHub: github.com/thereeling/vacci-date

- A web-based dating application that allows users who are vaccinated against COVID-19 to meet others like themselves through profile matching based on user preferences.
- Constructed back-end user model with like/dislike functionality and automated matching mutations; configured front-end user profile form; set up Tailwind CSS framework for styling
- Tools / Languages: JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Tailwind, GraphQL, REACT, State

## Yafoodle | UI & Local Storage

Deployed: markcyg.github.io/Yafoodle | GitHub: github.com/MarkCyg/Yafoodle

- A search engine that provides the user 5 random recipes & videos based on keywords and specified cuisine types / dietary restrictions. Users can bookmark their favorite recipes for later.
- Spearheaded local storage bookmarking feature; refined user interface
- Tools / Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Edamam & Youtube APIs, AJAX, local storage

#### **RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE**

St. Edmund's Retreat | Mystic, CT

August 2015 - August 2020

Marketing & Creative Director (2019) | Director of Digital Communications (2016)

- Designed, built and maintained organization website; optimized for mobile
- Integrated 3rd party CRM and fundraiser software
- Composed & designed email templates / printed marketing materials
- Managed campus IT—including the local network, hardware & software on all devices
- Helped grow annual summer gala revenue over 200% in three years by leveraging new tech

## **ADDITIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE**

St. Bernard School | Uncasville, CT

September 2020 - Present

High School Theology Teacher

- Provided hybrid instruction during the COVID-19 pandemic
- Redesigned curriculum for better learning outcomes and utilized modern EdTech platforms

St. Michael Parish | Pawcatuck, CT

November 2015 - Present

Professional Cantor, Choral Section Leader, Schola Director

Franciscan University | Steubenville, OH

July 2012 - July 2015

Residence Director

#### **EDUCATION**

Coding Boot Camp Certificate | University of Connecticut

January 2022

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills for the MERN stack.

**Bachelor of Arts** | Franciscan University of Steubenville, OH Double-major with a 3.54 GPA May 2012